Miguel A. Coronel

Flectronic Engineer

I worked in the oil & gas industry for several years and that experience allowed me to build many skills which have enriched my personal and professional life, but, after the Covid pandemic, I decided to take a turn on my career path. My biggest passion in university was coding and I never stopped coding. It became my hobby. Now, I am trying to build a career doing what I love. Check my web page to take a look at my latest personal projects.

O Ciudad Autónoma de Buenos Aires, Argentina

+54 9 11 3669 3875

migcoronel.com

linkedin.com/in/migcoronel codewars.com/users/migcoronel

PROFESSIONAL SKILLS

- Self-driven and results-driven engineer. As a field engineer I learned to achieve goals on time without the necessity of being supervised.
- Worked in a high pressure environment and delivered directly to clients.
- Autodidact. When I have a problem or an obstacle, I go to the documentation to better understand the root of the problem and then try to solve it from there.
- Always involved in Root Cause Analysis (RCA) after a failure and writing Lesson Learned Reports to prevent future failures.
- Lead small technical groups to achieve special task in different areas.
- Worked in English speaking professional environment.

CODING PERSONAL PROJECTS

DB WebApp

- Fully responsive WebApp UI to CRUD entries on a SQL DB.
- Developed with Spring Boot and Vaadin Java frameworks.
- Deployed inside Docker containers on an AWS EC2 instance.
- Check it on the link of my personal web page (migcoronel.com).

Rest API

- REST API to deal with GET, PUT, POST and DELETE orders to alter a SQL DB through JPA.
- Developed with Spring Boot Java framework.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Field Engineer M/LWD 3 (GG8)

Weatherford Internacional de Argentina

03/2016 - 07/2020 Weatherford is a global oil & gas company founded in Texas, US. Argentina

Responsabilities

- Teach new employees as field specialist, guide them through their career path inside the company.
- Test and prepare documentation about new technologies before going to field.
- Prepare M/LWD drilling tools before operations (including programming and testing) and deploy them in the field.

Contact: Sebastian Grispino - +54 9 299 606 1089

Field Operations Specialist M/LWD 3 (GG7)

Weatherford de Venezuela

10/2011 - 10/2015 Contact: Paul Fuenmayor - fuenmayorpe@gmail.com Venezuela

EDUCATION

Electronic Engineer

Mention: Automation and Process Control Universidad Rafael Belloso Chacín (URBE)

09/2007 - 07/2011 Maracaibo - Venezuela

Excelled at all coding subjects at university:

SOFT SKILLS

Adaptability Critical Thinking

Leadership Problem

Teamwor

LANGUAGES / TECHS

Spring Boot framework

Vaadin framework

MySQL and JPA

Git (Version Control)

Docker

lava

AWS / EC2

HTML / CSS

LANGUAGES

English

Full Professional Proficiency

Spanish

Native

PERSONAL REFERENCES

Justin Renneke

"Friend and Career Mentor"

rennekej@gmail.com - +1 (573) 694-8413

Franklin Piñerua

"Career Mentor"

+1 (713) 516-5638

INTERESTS / HOBBIES

Soccer P

Pets

Trading

CodeWars